# JORDAN HICKMAN

FULL STACK DEVELOPER \$816-820-3938

# • CONTACT •

816-820-3938 jdhickman816@outlook.com

• LINKS •

Linked In

Personal Portfolio Site

• SKILLS •

Git

HTML5

CSS3

C# Fundamentals

**JavaScript** 

**Bootstrap** 

jQuery

SQL

ASP.NET MVC

XML

JSON

React JS

Agile Project Management

# ■ WHO I AM

A dedicated, hardworking, self driven team mate who is looking for web development opportunities. Harnessing a positive attitude and wide skill set in addition to being a vocational graduate as a .NET Full Stack Developer. I possess 11 years of work force history primarily as an educator and team leader. Proven ability to establish and maintain excellent communication and relationships with clients. Committed to utilizing my skills to further the mission of a company.

# EDUCATION

.NET Full Stack Developer, Centriq Training, Kansas City

January 2021 — April 2021

March 2021 — March 2021

# **★** INDEPENDENT DEVELOPMENT PROJECTS

# **Small Business Project**

A static website for a mock business to promote educational classes of a specific subject. Using strictly custom HTML5 and CSS3 with restrictions on Bootstrap. This will have HTML pages for Contact, Class Schedules, Leaderships, and About Us styled with CSS.

#### Personal Portfolio Site

<u>jordanhickman.com/</u>; A self-made site to portray coding achievements in the Full Stack Development field. This site contains portfolio projects and resume and was created using JavaScript, jQuery, HTML5, and CSS3.

#### **Store Front**

Created a secure application for managing product data. Application is built to simulate an online store front with a shopping cart. Administrators have the ability to manage product, category and vendor data. Using SQL for databases.

### C# Dungeon Console Application

Created a Windows console application text-based Dungeon game. Using C# fundamentals, I created this by demonstrating logic, polymorphism, inheritance, fully qualified construction of classes, and a passion for early computer games.

# **Final Project**

Created a secure data driven ASP.NET MVC application for design through deployment for managing the tracking and organization of hardware and software within a company. Administrators have the ability to manage employee, department data and all details relating to assigned hardware.

March 2021 — March 2021

#### EMPLOYMENT HISTORY

# Barista at Filling Station Coffee, Kansas City, MO

June 2020 — Present

- Prepare and serve hot and cold beverages, such as coffee, espresso drinks, or teas.
- Describe menu items to customers or suggest products that might appeal to them.
- Receive and process customer payments.

# Bartender at The Big Rip Brewing Company, Kansas City, MO

June 2020 — Present

- Hold state and county requirement of liquor and food handler licenses.
- Actively listen to customers to determine beverage preferences and make recommendations.
- Eye for detail in developing new recipes and comprehension of drink mixing techniques.

# Production Coffee Roaster, Team Manager, Trainer at Hammerhand Coffee, Liberty, MO October 2016 — June 2020

- Became fluent in roasting coffee orders on a five kilo Mill City roaster.
- Highlighted qualities from coffee roasting to coffee extractions.
- Worked with owner to continuously seek out education for self and store and incorporated that knowledge into the evolving training program.

# Front-of-House Director, Team Manager, Trainer at Doughnut Lounge Cocktails and Cafe, Kansas City, MO

March 2021 — March 2021

- Collaborated with the owner prior to grand opening to establish front-of-house guidelines.
- Created training program for front-of-house, customer service, and coffee service standards.
- Fluent in all shift managing duties, such as, drawer counting, bank deposits, check writing, invoice payments, supervising team duties, and owning store key.
- Created accounts and business relationships with all suppliers for the store.

# Lead Barista, Team Manager, Trainer at Kaldi's Coffee, Kansas City, MO

October 2013 — October 2015

- Scheduled and implemented all store coffee education.
- Conducted pre-employment coffee tasting and knowledge evaluations during hiring process.
- Worked with Retail Store General Manager to continually evaluate and deliver Team Member training adherence and skill development results.
- Monitored espresso drinks, all versions of brew to order coffee, and tea and water quality and maintain adherence to company beverage standards.

# Concert Marketer, Street Team Leader at Mammoth Inc., Kansas City, MO

October 2011 — October 2014

- Promoted music and entertainment events for a large-scale music promotion business.
- Used communications skills to build relationships with local business owners.
- Actively advertised in more than 40 business locations bi-weekly.
- Developed advertisement strategies based on demographic data and event relevance.
- Recruited, trained, and coordinated new street team promoters.

# **¶** REFERENCES

### Alex Merrell from Hammerhand Coffee

alex@hammerhandcoffee.com · 417-631-1677

# Bri Burrows from Big Rip Brewing Company

bri@bigripbrewing.com · 816-309-2171